Guide to the Breed Collection of Maps, Documents, and Prints, 1545-1973
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Breed Collection of Maps, Documents, and Prints
1545-1973
Approximately 300 items
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Collection of maps, charts and atlas pages, documents, and illustrations depicting various regions of the globe ranging from the 16th to 19th centuries.
Scope and Content Note
Collection of maps, charts and atlas pages, documents, and illustrations depicting various regions of the globe ranging from the 16th to 19th centuries. Of particular note are maps of Great Britain, Germany, Italy, the North American colonies, and South America. The documents relate to Peter Chester, Colonial Governor of West Florida. All measurements are approximate.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Atlas Collection
Edward Lasker Collection of Atlases and Maps
Richmond John Rathbone Collection of Rare Maps
Vassar College Archives Maps Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Blaeu, Joan, 1596-1673; Blaeu, Willem, 1635-1701; Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638; Bowen, Emanuel, 1693 or 1694-1767; Chester, Peter, approximately 1717-1799; Clarke, W. B.; Danckerts, Justus, 1635-1701; Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720; Homann, Johann Baptist, 1663-1724; Jansson, Jan, 1588-1664; Kitchin, Thomas, 1719-1784; Moll, Herman, -1732; Morden, Robert, approximately 1650-1703; Ortelius, Abraham, 1527-1598; Popple, Henry, -1743; Seutter, Matthäus, 1678-1757; Tirion, Isaak, 1705-1769; Visscher, Nicolaes, 1649-1702; Wit, Frederik de, 1629 or 1630-1706
Places:
North America--History--Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; North America--Maps; Europe--Maps; Great Britain--Maps; Germany--Maps; Italy--Maps; United States--Maps; South America--Maps; West Florida--History--Sources
Document Types:
Maps; Manuscripts (documents); Prints (visual works); Title pages
VCL Categories:
Maps
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, July 2011. Updated October 2018 and January 2019. Last updated by Emma Gronbeck, September 2024.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Jocelyn Harrington Breed (VC 1936).
Arrangement
The maps are organized into series roughly by geographic area. There is considerable overlap between the sub-series, though, so careful browsing is required to complete a thorough search of the collection.
Within each series, maps are arranged in item number order.
Series List
- MAPS — AFRICA
- MAPS — ASIA
- MAPS — ATLANTIC OCEAN
- MAPS — AUSTRALIA
- MAPS — CANADA
- MAPS — CARIBBEAN
- MAPS — CENTRAL AMERICA
- MAPS — CUBA
- MAPS — EUROPE — COMPLETE
- MAPS — EUROPE — CENTRAL EUROPE
- MAPS — EUROPE — EASTERN EUROPE
- MAPS — EUROPE — BALKANS
- MAPS — EUROPE — MEDITERRANEAN SEA
- MAPS — EUROPE — TWO OR MORE COUNTRIES
- MAPS — EUROPE — DENMARK
- MAPS — EUROPE — FLANDERS
- MAPS — EUROPE — FRANCE
- MAPS — EUROPE — GERMANY
- MAPS — EUROPE — GREAT BRITAIN
- MAPS — EUROPE — HUNGARY
- MAPS — EUROPE — ITALY
- MAPS — EUROPE — LITHUANIA
- MAPS — EUROPE — LUXEMBOURG
- MAPS — EUROPE — NETHERLANDS
- MAPS — EUROPE — PORTUGAL
- MAPS — EUROPE — RUSSIA
- MAPS — EUROPE — SPAIN
- MAPS — EUROPE — SWITZERLAND
- MAPS — MEXICO
- MAPS — NEAR EAST
- MAPS — NORTH AMERICA
- MAPS — PACIFIC OCEAN
- MAPS — POLAR REGIONS
- MAPS — ROMAN EMPIRE
- MAPS — SOLAR SYSTEM
- MAPS — SOUTH AMERICA
- MAPS — UNITED STATES
- MAPS — WEST INDIES
- MAPS — WESTERN HEMISPHERE
- MAPS — WORLD
- MAPS — MISCELLANEOUS
- MISCELLANEOUS PIECES
- DOCUMENTS
- PRINTS AND ILLUSTRATIONS
Container List
- MAPS — AFRICA
  - A New Map of Egypt from the latest authorities, by John Cary, Engineer, 1811; (19.25 x 23.5 | tinted) (021 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - A New and Correct Map of Africa laid down from the most Exact Observations and Discoveries, undated; (24.75 x 41 | tinted; folded) (083 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Insets: Customs of the natives; View of Cape of Good Hope.
  - Fezzae et Marocchi regna Africae celeberrima, Describebat Abrah: [Abraham Ortelius, 1527-1598], undated; (19 x 22 | tinted) (084 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text containing descriptions of Fessanvm and Mavrocanvm attached.
    — Total of 3 leaves joined together, unnumbered.
  - To the Right and Honorable Charles Earl of Peterborow and Monmouth, etc. This map of Africa... is most humbly dedicated by: [Herman Moll] Geographer, [London], undated; (24.5 x 41 | tinted; folded) (085 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Insets: View of Cape of Good Hope with 3 plans of fortifications.
  - Totius Africae Nova Repraesentatio..., a Io Baptista Homanno [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724]... Norimbergae, undated; (tinted and decorated) (086 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Africa, According to Newest and most Exact Observations By Herman Moll Geographer, undated; (10 x 14.5 | black and white) (238 (Box 1))
  - Aphricae Tabvla I, [Northwest Africa and southern coast of Spain], 1552; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (239 (Box 1))
    — In pencil: "Munster's Ptolemy 1552."
    — Text on verso: "Aphricae.. ."
- MAPS — ASIA
  - Tabula Tartariae et majoris partis Regni Chinae, editae a [Frederik de Wit, 1629 or 1630-1706] [Amsterdam], undated; (19 x 23 | black and white) (022 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Asiae: Nova Descriptio Auctore Iodoco Hondio, undated; (15.5 x 20 | tinted) (023 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — On verso: pages 343-344, "Novvelle Asie."
    — Decorative motif at center of each page.
    — "Nnnnnnn" on lower part of right-hand page.
  - A New and Correct Map of Asia laid down from the most Exact Observations and Discoveries..., London, Printed and sold by John Bowles, undated; (24 x 41 | tinted; folded) (087 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Insets: Christian Church at Jerusalem; Incarnations of the god Wistnou; Group of idols worshipped in Asia.
  - Tabula Asiae III, 1545; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (240 (Box 1))
    — Armenia and Caspian Sea.
    — In pencil: "Munster's Ptolemy 1545."
    — Text on verso: "Tertia Asiae.. ."
  - Tabula Asiae IIII, 1552; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (241 (Box 1))
    — Near East
    — Text on verso: "Qvarta.. ."
  - Asia recens summa cura..., Auct. Henr. Hondio, (23.25 x 19.5 | tinted) (275 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text in Dutch on reverse.
    — Small rips, tears and slight water damage.
  - To the Right Honourable William, Lord Cowper.. ., Herman Moll, D. Midwinter, [Thomas Bowles], and Philip Overton, London, approximately 1721-1724; (22.5 x 38 | large folio) (282 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Asia and Africa.
    — 7 insets. Wind vectors and compass rose.
- MAPS — ATLANTIC OCEAN
  - Chart shewing the tracks across the North Atlantic Ocean of Don Christopher Columbus. (1st-4th voyages). Published By George P. Putnam, New York, undated; (11.5 x 19 | black and white) (024 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Carte Réduite de l'Ocean Occidental.. ., 1776; (13 x 19.5 | tinted) (025 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — North Atlantic 50 Lat. to the equator, showing parts of coasts of North and South America, Europe, and Africa.
  - A New Map, or Chart in Mercators Projection, of the Western or Atlantic Ocean, with part of Europe, Africa and America, [after 1764 Aug 25]; (18.5 x 22 | black and white) (026 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Oceano Atlantico, Por D. Tomas Lopez, 1788; (7 x 7 | black and white) (222 (Box 2))
    — Area adjacent to the Tropic of Cancer.
- MAPS — AUSTRALIA
  - A Map of New South Wales showing Stock Routes, Tanks, Wells, and Trucking Stations, Sydney & Melbourne, The Picturesque Atlas Pub. Co., undated; (17 x 25.75 | black and white with red lines and dots; in 2 pieces) (088 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - A Map of Victoria, Showing Average Annual Rainfall, Comp. From records supplied by the Government Astronomer, R. L. J. Ellery..., undated; (12.5 x 17 | black and white and blue; in 2 pieces) (089 (Map Case Drawer 13))
- MAPS — CANADA
  - Nieuwe Kaart Van Kanada, De Landen aas de Hudsons Baay en de Noordwestlyke... Te Amsterdam by [Isaak Tirion, 1705-1769], (14 x 18 | black and white) (030 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - British Colonies in North America, undated; (8 x 10 | tinted) (223 (Box 2))
- MAPS — CARIBBEAN
  - Mappa Aestivarum Insularum... / A Mapp of the Sommer Ilands... Amstelodamensis, Abraham Goos, 1626, [1631?]; (17 x 22 | black and white) (031 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text on verso of pages 41-42.
    — Date should perhaps be 1622. See list at right-hand bottom of map.
- MAPS — CENTRAL AMERICA
  - Kaart van de Laudengte van Panama, Volgens de Spaanische astekeningen opgemaakt, undated; (16 x 18.5 | tinted) (032 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — In pencil: "Isaak Tirion."
- MAPS — CUBA
  - The Form of Landing our Troops on the Island of Cuba for the Besieging of the Havana, 1762, Engraved for the London Magazine, undated; (8 x 11 | black and white) (225 (Box 2))
    — 6 ships and ships' boats loaded with troops.
  - A New Map of the Island of Cuba with correct Plans of all the Principal Ports and Harbours it contains, J. Gibson sculp., undated; (12.5 x 13.75 | tinted) (244 (Box 1))
- MAPS — EUROPE — COMPLETE
  - A New Map of Europe done from the most Accurate Observations Communicated to the Royal Society at London..., London, Christopher Browne, undated; (24.5 x 41 | tinted and decorated; folded) (098 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Insets: Battles and fortifications relating to Queen Ann's victories over the French.
  - To her most Sacred Majesty Ann Queen of Great Britain, France & Ireland. This map of Europe... is dedicated by... Herman Moll Geographer, [London], 1708; (24.5 x 40.5 | tinted and decorated; folded) (215 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Inset: Map of waterway connecting the Volga and the Don in Russia.
  - Europe with its respective divisions, [London] Published by J. Rowe, 1706; (6 x 7.25 | tinted) (226 (Box 2))
  - Theatrum historicum ad annum christi quadragentesimum in quo tum Imperii Romani barbarorum.. ., P. Mortimer. Amsteredam, undated; (32.5 x 28.5, including frame and matting) (288 (Framed Storage 2.7))
- MAPS — EUROPE — CENTRAL EUROPE
  - Silesiae Ductus Nova Et Accurata Description, Joannes Janssonius [Jan Jansson, 1588-1664] Excu., undated; (19 x 22 | tinted) (033 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text on verso: unnumbered page and page 524.
  - Ducatus Silesiae Glogani Vera Delineatio Secundâ curâ ac labore consecta A Iona Sculteto Sprotta Silesio, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (091 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text on verso of pages 61-62.
  - Moravia Marchionatus, auctore I. A. Comenio., Amstelodami, Guiljelm Blaeuw [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?], exeudit., undated; (20 x 24.25 | tinted and decorated) (092 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 75-76): "Morvia."
  - Regni Poloniae et Ducatus Lithuaniae, Voliniae, Podoliae, Ucraniae, Prussiae et Curlandiae descriptio emendata per [Justus Danckerts, 1635-1701], Amstelodami..., undated; (20.5 x 24 | tinted) (093 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Silesiae Ducatus Accurata et vera delineation. Viris magnific acgenerosis.. ., undated (094 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Stiria Steyrmarck, undated (095 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Tabula Ductus Carnioliae Vindorum Marchiae et Histriae.. ., Io. Bapt. Homanno [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724] S.C.M. Geogr. Noribergae.. ., undated; (20.25 x 24.5 | tinted and decorated) (096 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Insets: St. Laybach and Cirknitzer See.
    — Region northeast of Adriatic Sea. Principal country shown is "Crain." Trieste on the Adriatic is included.
  - Regni Polonie, Et Ducatus, Lithvaniae Voliniae, Podoliae, Vcraniae, Prvssiae, Livoniae, et Cvrlandiae.. ., Amstelodami, [Frederik de Wit, 1629 or 1630-1706]..., undated; (22 x 20.5 | tinted) (277 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Significant tears, rips and pieces falling off.
  - Darstellung des Grundisses und Prospectus der Konigl Preussisch Magdeburgischen und des Saal-Crayses Haupt Stadt Halle.. ., Homann's Heirs (after J.B. & J.C. Homann). Nuremberg, approximately 1770; (19 x 23) (281 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Originally published approximately 1727.
- MAPS — EUROPE — EASTERN EUROPE
  - The Map of Moscovy, Poland, Little Tartary, and ye Black Sea etc... by [Herman Moll] Geographer, undated; (24.5 x 42 | tinted and decorated) (214 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Inset: Northern Russia.
    — Done by the Czar's order (Peter Alexovitz).
- MAPS — EUROPE — BALKANS
  - Daciarum, Moesiarumque, vetus descriptio, Abrahami Ortelij [Abraham Ortelius, 1527-1598], 1595; (17 x 22.5 | colored boundary lines) (027 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — European Turkey: Rumania, Moesia.
  - Walachia, Servia, Bulgaria, Romania. Per Gerardum Mercatorem, Guiljelmus, Blaeu [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?)], undated; (19 x 22.5 | tinted) (028 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text on verso - unnumbered pages.
  - Goritiae, Karstii, Chaczeolae, Carniolae, Histriae, et Windorum Marchae descrip, undated; (9 x 13.75 | tinted; edges folded under) (242 (Box 1))
    — Parts of Yugoslavia and Rumania.
  - Carniola, Cilia Comitatus et Windorum Marchia, Ger. Mercatore auctore. Guiljelm Blaeu [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?)] excudit, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (274 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text on verso of pages 79-80.
    — Could be Yugoslavia.
- MAPS — EUROPE — MEDITERRANEAN SEA
  - Chart of the Mediterranean Sea, Drawn and Engraved for Thomson's New General Atlas, 1817; (21 x 27.75 | tinted) (117 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Tabula Neoterica Crete Sive Candie Insule, undated; (18 x 24 | tinted) (118 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Harbor maps inset.
  - Plan Géometral de la Ville et de la Montagne de Gibraltar..., Par L. Denis Géographe et Auteur du Conducteur Francais, 1781; (18 x 26 | tinted) (119 (Map Case Drawer 14))
- MAPS — EUROPE — TWO OR MORE COUNTRIES
  - A New Map of Denmark and Sweden According to the Newest and most Exact Observations By [Herman Moll] Geographer, undated; (24.5 x 40.5 | tinted; folded) (097 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Tabula Episcopatuum Leodiensis et Coloniensis Trevirensis..., per [Theodore Danckerts], [Amstelodami], undated; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted and decorated) (102 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Flanders and Germany.
    — Treveri (peoples); Trier (city); Leodium (Liege in Belgium).
  - Tabula Rheni et Mosae.. ., Exc: Guiljel. Blaeuw [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?)], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (103 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Flanders and Germany — Rhine and Meuse.
    — Text on verso of pages 15-16.
  - Kaerte van de vier Ambachten, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (104 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Flanders and Netherlands.
    — Text on verso of pages 121-122.
  - Castellania Furnensis, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (105 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 91-92): "Castellania Fvrnensis."
  - Wasia, t' land van Waes, Antonius Sanderus, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (106 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 123-24): "Wasia.. ."
  - 6 leaves by Herman Moll, 1712-1714 (114 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Includes 3 maps:
    — A New and Exact Map of France..., undated (2 leaves)
    — A New Map of Italy Distinguishing all the Sovreignties in it whether States, Kingsoms, Butchies, Principalities, Republics etc.. ., 1714 (2 leaves)
    — A New Map of Germany, Hungary, Transylvania and the Suisse, 1712 (2 leaves)
  - Lotharingle et Utriusque Alsatiae.. ., delineatio per [Theodore Danckerts], undated; (20.5 x 24.25 | tinted and decorated) (115 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Germany, Netherlands and France.
  - Nova Graecia XXII, Nova Tabula, undated; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (252 (Box 1))
    — Greece and Asia Minor.
  - Regni Sueciae,Tabula Generalis..., Per. [Frederik de Wit, 1629 or 1630-1706] Amstelodami..., (22.75 x 20.75 | tinted) (279 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Small tear at bottom of map.
- MAPS — EUROPE — DENMARK
  - Iutia Septentrionalis, per Gerardum Mercatorem, undated; (19.5 x 23 | tinted) (034 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text in French on verso (unnumbered pages): "La Jvtie septentrionale."
- MAPS — EUROPE — FLANDERS
  - Nova Totius Belgii sive Germaniae Interioris..., Amstelodami, apud Ioannem Ianssonium [Jan Jansson, 1588-1664], undated; (19.75 x 23.25 | tinted) (035 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text in Dutch on verso (unnumbered pages): "Nederlant."
  - Dioecesis Leodiensis Accurata Tebula, Amstelodami, Sumptibus Henrici Hondii, undated; (19.5 x 23 | tinted and decorated) (036 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text in French on verso (unnumbered pages): "L'Eveshe de Liege."
  - [Flandria Teutonica], (12 x 20 | tinted; half of map missing) (037 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text on verso (p.84) "Flandria Tevtonica."
  - Leodiensis Diocesis, Amsterdami, apud Guiljelmum et Ioannem Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu and Joan Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (099 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Liege.
    — Text on verso of page 255b.
  - Prima pars Brabantiae cuius caput Lovanivm, auctore Michaele Florentio a Langren. Guiljelmus Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu] excudit., undated; (20 x 24 |tinted and decorated) (100 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 7-8): "... Lovanivm."
  - Tabula generalis totius Belgii qua Provinvia XVII, Infer. Germaniae... a Iohanne Baptista Homanno [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], Norimbergae, undated; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted) (101 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Belgii Universi seu Inferioris Germaniae..., a Tobia Majero... cura et studio Homannianorum Heredum, 1747, 1748; (21.25 x 24.75 | tinted) (107 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Flandria et Zeelandia Comitatvs, apud Guiljelmum Blaeuw [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?)], undated; (20.25 x 23.75 | tinted and decorated) (108 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 29-30): "Flandria Comitatvs."
  - Plan of the situation where the Battle of Ramillies was fought May ye 23d 1706: designed upon the spot by G. L. Mosburger..., undated; (16 x 20.5 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
    — One of 10 illustrations made for Tyndal's continuation of Rapin's History of England.
- MAPS — EUROPE— FRANCE
  - Comitatus Burgundiae.. ., per Nicolm. Visscher [Nicolaes Visscher, 1649-1702], [Amsterdam]: Bat., undated; (20.25 x 24.25 | colored boundary lines and decorations) (109 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Comitatuum Hannoniae et Nambrci descriptio, Amsterdami, apud Guiljelmii et Ioannem Blaeu [ Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu and Joan Blaeu], undated; (20.5 x 24 | tinted) (110 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 141-142): "Hannonia Comitatvs."
  - France, by A. K. Johnston, Edinburgh and Glasgow, undated; (21.5 x 26 | black and white with colored lineation) (111 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — National Atlas, page 7.
  - Carte nouvelle du Gouvernement General de La Champagne par le Sr. Robert de Vaugondy, A Paris chez le Sr. De La Marche, 1783; (27.75 x 21 | colored boundaries) (112 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — List of names at right side.
  - Diocese de Nismes... par J.B. Nolin. A Paris, chez Mondhare et Jean rue St. Jean de Beauvais, 1787; (20 x 25.75 | colored boundaries) (113 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Illustrations in margins.
  - A Map of the Country about Tournay, Lille, Douai, Arras, Valencienes, etc., By Cha: Price and Iohn Senex Geographers, undated; (10 x 12.5 | black and white) (245 (Box 1))
    — Page 460.
  - Tabula Europae III, undated; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (246 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso: "Gallia... "
  - A map of France.. ., undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
  - Plan of the City and Citadel of Lisle, [1708]; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
- MAPS — EUROPE — GERMANY
  - Scenographia Urbium Silasiae, Tab. IV, entworfen von F. B. Werner Siles. und ausgefertiget von Homaennischen Erben, Nurnberg, 1738; (20.5 x 24 | tinted) (015 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Views of 9 towns.
  - Scenographia Urbium Silasiae, Tab. V, entworfen von F. B. Werner u. herausgegeben von Homaennischen Erben. Nurnberg, 1738; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted) (016 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Views of 7 towns.
  - Scenographia Urbium Silasiae, Tab. VII, entworfen von F. B. Werner u. herausgegeben von Homaennischen Erben. Nurnberg, 1738; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted) (017 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Bavaria ducatus, Per Ger. Mercatorem, apud Guiljelmum Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?)Blaeu], undated; (19 x 22 | tinted) (039 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text for "Bavaria dvcatvs" attached, total of 3 sheets.
  - Palatinatvs Bavariae, Amsterdami, Excudit Guiljelmus Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (19 x 22.25 | tinted) (041 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text on verso (pages not numbered).
  - Territorium Argentoratense, Ioannes Ianssonius [Jan Jansson, 1588-1664] excudit., undated; (19.5 x 23 | tinted) (042 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Text in French on verso (unnumbered pages): "Le Territoire de Strasbovrg."
  - Territorium Norimbergense, Amstelodami exc. Guiljelm. Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (19 x 22.5 | tinted) (044 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Inset: City of Nvrnberg.
    — Text in Latin on verso: "Norimbergense Territ."
  - [Map of wooded and farming country crossed by the Fossa Friderico passing through Muelrose], undated; (22 x 25.5 | black and white) (124 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Name of Fridericus Guiljelmus, Electoris Brandenburgici appears in descriptive material.
  - Alemannia sive Svevia svperior, A Christophoro Hurtero, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (125 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 319-320).
  - Bavaria ducatus, Per. Ger. Mercatorem, Apud Guiljelmum Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?)Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (126 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 87-88).
  - Carte itineraire par le Pays de l' Electorat de Saxe..., publiee par les foins des Heritiers de Homann l' An 1752, (21.75 x 26 | decorated in black and white, boundaries and cities tinted) (127 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Comitatus Hennebergensis, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (128 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 303-304).
  - Comitatus Marchia et Ravensberg, undated; (20 x 23.75 | tinted) (129 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 253-254): "Comitatvs Marcha et Ravensberg."
  - Cursus Rheni a Basilea usque ad Bonnam, III... ,per Homannianos Heredes Noribergae, undated; (20.25 x 24.5 | tinted) (130 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Ducatus Brunsuicensis..., edita cura Ioh. Bapt. Homanni [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], undated; (20.25 x 24.5 | tinted) (131 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Ducatus Bronsuincensis.. ., Casparo Dauthendeij, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (132 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 217-218): "Bronsvincensis Dvcatvs" (Brunswick).
  - Ducatus Lunenburgensis..., auctore Iohanne Mellingero. Amstelodami, Guiljelm. Blaewx [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu] excudit, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (133 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 215-216).
  - Ducatus Saxoniae superioris..., per Fridericum Zollmannum in publicum emissus ab Homannianis Heredibus, Norib. A 1732... Tab. III, (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted) (134 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Ducatus Silesiae Schwidnicensis, authore Friderico Kuhnovio..., undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (135 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (page 71): "Schwidnicensis Dvcatvs."
  - Episcopatus Halberstat, Amstlaedami, apud Joannem Blaew [Joan Blaeu, 1596-1673], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (136 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (page 224b): "Halberstadiensis episcopatvs."
  - Erpach Comitatvs, Amstelodami, Guiljelmus Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (137 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (page 305): "Erpach Comitatvs."
  - Franconia Vulgo Franctenlandt, excudit Guiljelmus Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (138 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 299-300).